# 啤酒加热以后有一种枣香味
The beer has a date-like aroma after heating.
# 精华在这儿呢
The essence is here.
# 你看这水都变成什么颜色了
See what color does the water change into?
# 这是淮扬菜的一个老菜 太漂亮了
This is a traditional Huaiyang cuisine. Very beautiful!
# 我做这啤酒鸭跟他们做的还不一样
I cook the beer braised duck differently from others
# 我这是汤 汤菜
Mine is soup, a soup dish.
# 我们把这鸭子弄干净了
Let’s clean the duck
# 先出出水 凉水下锅
Parboil it first. Put it in cold water (then boil).
# 这是一个樱桃谷鸭
This is a Pekin.
# 这鸭子我们先给它煮上
Let’s boil the duck first.
# 然后给它放点葱姜去腥 黄酒
Then we add some spring onions and ginger to remove the gamey taste, and some Huangjiu rice wine.
# 鸭子光一个光板鸭子不行啊
Duck (cuisine) is not going to make it with just a duck
# 今天要包翡翠饺
Today we are making “jade dumplings” (to pair with it).
# 搁点（黄酒） 搁点盐
Add some (Huangjiu rice wine) and salt
# 搁点酱油 包饺子就是饺子馅
Add some soy sauce. When making dumplings, make dumpling fillings.
# 老抽
Dark soy sauce
# 这个馅一般的咱们用肉馅最好
It is best to use meat filling for these dumplings
# 因为肉馅它香
Because meat filling is more aromatic.
# 我先把它打了
Let me mix it first.
# 让这馅嫩一点 我们加点水
To make the filling tender, we add some water.
# 然后我再切点葱姜
Then I cut some spring onions and ginger.
# 这是淮阳菜的一个老菜
This is a traditional Huai Yang cuisine.
# 啤酒清炖牛肉 啤酒清炖鸭 啤酒清炖鸡
Beer braised beef, beer braised duck, beer braised chicken
# 啤酒加热以后 由于酒的醇度的挥发
After heating the beer, the alcohol evaporated
# 这酒喝到嘴里头有一种枣香味儿
Leaving a date-like flavor when you taste the beer
# 也就是它的酒曲的香味
This is the aroma from the brewer’s yeast
# 葱姜都弄好了
Spring onions and gingers are in.
# 我们给它搁点香油
Let’s add some sesame oil.
# 和馅必须要搁香油
One must add sesame oil when making the filling
# 馅儿弄好了 咱们把面和上
The filling is ready, let’s mix the dough.
# 这是菠菜搁上水用粉碎机把它打成蓉
This is spinach, add some water and blend it.
# 这叫翡翠饺
This is called jade dumplings
# 用这菠菜蓉可以染虾球 叫翡翠虾
The spinach puree can color shrimp balls and the dish is called jade shrimp.
# 鸡片叫翡翠鸡片
(use it on) chicken fillet called jade chicken fillet
# 不够绿待会我再给它处理一下
It is not green enough. I will deal with it later.
# 咱们给它饧上
Let the dough rest.
# 面饧好了 咱们看鸭子了
The dough is resting. Let’s check on the duck.
# 这个鸭子特别容易熟
This duck is easily cooked well-done
# 用高压锅二十分钟
20 minutes if using a pressure cooker,
# 要煮的话四十分钟就可以了
Or boiling in a pot for 40 minutes.
# 我们现在给它搁到高压锅里边
Now we transfer it into a pressure cooker.
# 装不下 这锅不够大
The pot is not big enough (for the duck)
# 这脖子得要
Keep the duck neck.
# 碍事儿的地儿就给它去了
Remove the parts that get in the way.
# 因地制宜 这就行了
Adapt to our conditions, that’s all.
# 原汤 煮鸭子的原汤
The original soup which we cook the duck in.
# 葱姜 酒都搁完了
Add spring onions, ginger and wine.
# 大爷 搁一香菜根
Da Ye, add a piece of cilantro root.
# （电高压锅）压二十分钟
(electric pressure cooker) cook 20 minutes
# 四儿 我们刚才用的是（菠菜）水
Si er, we used (spinach) juice
# 但是说现在这个面不是很绿
But now that the dough is not green enough
# 我们要用另外的一种提取方法
We will use another method to extract (the green color)
# 把这过一下箩
Filter it (the spinach puree)
# 把菠菜里边的渣滓给它去掉
Remove the residual of the spinach
# 好现在烧开
Now we boil it
# 最顶级的精华在这儿呢
The essence is here!
# 你看一会儿一开锅
See, when it boils
# 浮上来的沫子是精华
The foam floating on top is the essence.
# 底下就变成白水了
Underneath is just plain water
# 这精华的绿度要超过水的绿色
The essence is much greener than the water
# 你看这水
Look at the water
# 四儿你看精华在这儿呢
Si er, see the essence is right here
# 你看这水都变成什么颜色了
See what color does the water turned into
# 水现在已经没有颜色了 变成清水了
The water is colorless now, becoming clear water.
# 这个夏天因为它凉的慢
In summer, it cools down slowly
# 我们要弄多的话
If we make a large amount
# 这菠菜时间长了会变色
The spinach will change color over time.
# 最好现在要有条件的话
It is better, if available,
# 我们上边可以搁两块冰块
to put several pieces of ice on top
# 让它迅速的降温
To help it cool down quickly.
# 加了两块冰块
We added some ice cubes.
# 要用这个染虾仁 用这个染鸡片
Use this (foam) to color the shrimp or chicken fillet
# 用这个去和面
Use it to make the dough.
# 这冰块还有一个最大的好处是什么
The biggest advantage of using ice
# 它使这颜色更绿
Is to make the color greener.
# 这就是后来说的
This is as the saying goes,
# 绿颜色的菜拿凉水过凉 越凉越好
“Cool the green vegetables with cold water, the colder the better”.
# 为什么你多来两趟有好处
It is beneficial for you to come here more frequently
# 跟着大爷学点老知识
Follow Da Ye to learn some legacy knowledge.
# 你再搁水稀了 这颜色还是上不来
If you add more water the dough would be too soft while the color is still not (green) enough
# 我给拿这边来 搁案板上和
Let me take it here, knead on the pastry board
# 而且面染的要比别的要绿一点
The dough needs to be colored greener than others (shrimp or chicken)
# 因为它下锅以后还有一种脱色
Because it will fade a bit during cooking
# 我们把它和润了
Let’s knead the dough smoothly
# 行了 再饧一会儿咱就可以包饺子了
OK, let it rest a while then we can make dumplings
# 咱们这饺子不像
The dumplings we make today is not as big
# 咱们吃的饺子那么大 要小
as the normal dumplings. It is smaller.
# 翡翠饺子翡翠面
Jade dumplings, jade noodles
# 来碗翡翠面 烫几个活虾仁 虾倍儿红
Cook a bowl of jade noodles, boil several fresh shrimps. The shrimps are ruby
# 鲜虾翡翠面 清汤的
Fresh shrimps with jade noodles, in light soup
# 看着啊咱们包饺子了
Look, we are making dumplings
# 这可以挤 挤饺子 一个
You can squeeze the wrapper, squeeze, one done.
# 有时候高档宴会
Sometimes in a luxury banquet,
# 我们让饺子还得让它好看
We need to make the dumplings look pretty
# 有可能拿剪子给它铰了去
We may trim (the edge) with scissors
# 这都不齐 给它铰齐了不就完了吗
This is not even. Trim it evenly, right?
# 说就行了吧
This is good.
# 这鸭子就好了 现在开始改刀
The duck is cooked. Now we cut it into pieces
# 把它端出来 我们篦出点汤来
Take it out. We filter out some soup
# 这汤很香
The soup smells great
# 剩下汤我们就不用了
We discard the rest of the soup.
# 我们就给它冲凉了 要不然下不了手
We rinse it with cold water to cool it down, otherwise it is too hot for us to take.
# 饺子包好了
The dumplings are made
# 为了怕它风干 用布咱盖一下
To prevent them from getting too dry, we cover them with cloth
# 二伯饺子包好了 鸭子要改改刀
Er Bai made the dumplings. The duck need to be cut into pieces
# 鸭脖子
Duck neck
# 这鸭子一分为二 我们洗洗它
Cut the duck in half. We will wash it
# 为什么煮鸭子水要宽敞
Why do we cook the duck in large amount of water?
# 这膛里边还有一些淤血
Because there is some blood remaining in its cavity
# 这鸭斩件也需要一个技术
Cutting the duck requires skills
# 摆好了整齐
Set the plate, neatly
# 家里边吃的不用脱骨了 蒸完了还更香
No need to debone at home. It tastes better after steaming (bone-in)
# 冬天讲就喝鸡汤 夏天讲就喝鸭汤
It is seasonal and cultural to have chicken soup in winter and duck soup in summer
# 鸭是属于凉性 喝完了以后不上火
Duck is cool-natured, having it will not cause yeet hay
# 大爷在煮的时候加了好多姜
Da Ye added a lot of ginger when cook it
# 给它平衡了
Balanced it
# 这个都给它分好 这是鸭腿
Separate them well. This is the duck leg.
# 这块儿这是最经典的一块儿肉 鸭脯
This piece is the most classic one, duck breast
# 这是肉最多的这块儿
This piece contains the most meat
# 你看这两个鸭脯 好看吧
Look at the two pieces of duck breast, gorgeous.
# 改成多少块呢 要改成十块
How many pieces do we cut them into? ten!
# 好看吧 这时候咱们开始调味了
Isn’t it beautiful? Now let’s season it.
# 我们是啤酒鸭 少不了啤酒
We make beer braised duck, be generous with the beer
# 什么啤酒都可以 尽量别用黑啤酒
Any beer will do, just avoid stout if possible
# 有食欲 这啤酒可多可少 也可以少一点
It looks tempting! -The amount of beer is flexible, we can use less.
# 还得搁点黄酒
And we need some Huangjiu rice wine
# 来找一个小盘给它压上点
Use a small plate to press on it
# 压的目的就别让这肉散了
The goal is to prevent the meat from falling apart
# 保持它的形状 这是一个小窍门
Keep it in shape. This is a small trick.
# 搁点黄酒
Add some Huangjiu rice wine.
# 我们这鸭子前期
When we precooked the duck,
# 已经搁了葱姜了 这回要少搁
We already added spring onions and ginger. Now we should add less (of them)
# 有的人一搁搁葱姜搁的特别多
Some people add too many spring onions and ginger
# 全是葱姜味 也不行 一样两片
(the dish) is filled with the taste of spring onions and ginger, which is not good. A couple of slices each are sufficient.
# 这点汤不够 我们这还留了点鸭汤
The soup is not enough. We kept some duck soup.
# 把这鸭汤把油要去干净
Remove the duck fat oil
# 一只鸭子将近要出半斤左右的油
Each duck produces about half jin (250 g) of fat oil
# 出油量很大 尤其咱们北京这填鸭
That is a lot of oil, especially our Peking duck.
# 盐 白胡椒
Salt, white pepper
# 因为这啤酒发苦 稍微补一点糖
Because the beer tastes bitter, we add some white sugar
# 白糖也提鲜 味精什么的咱就不搁了
White sugar also improves savory taste, omitting the need of MSG
# 鸡精也不搁了 为什么
Also no need for chicken bouillon powder, why?
# 我们这原料都非常新鲜
Because our ingredients are very fresh
# 蒸一小时
Steam for one hour
# 另外这时间还有一个另定
Notice on alteration of cook time
# 如果煮鸭子煮的比较烂糊
If we precooked the duck to very soft texture,
# 我们就可以蒸四十分钟
We can steam for only 40 minutes.
# 如果这鸭子欠点儿火
If the duck is a bit raw
# 我们就要蒸一小时
We need to steam for an hour.
# 鸭子也蒸了快一小时了
The duck has been steamed for about an hour
# 马上就出锅了 菠饺啤酒清炖鸭
Almost ready! Spinach dumplings with beer braised duck
# 这是个夏季的一个汤菜
This is a soup dish for summer
# 汤菜在宴会里边它也算一个主菜
Soup dish is one of the main dishes in a banquet.
# 这汤出锅了
The soup dish is cooked
# 然后我们把这个葱拣出来
Then we pick out the spring onions
# 刚才搁的是两片葱 两片姜
We added two pieces of spring onions, two slices of ginger
# 然后把这盘儿起了
Take the small plate out
# 这形状还是这么整的 还是这么整齐
The shape (of the duck pieces) is maintained neatly
# 饺子马上就得  泡好的枸杞烫一下
Dumplings are almost ready, blanch the soaked wolfberries
# 这饺子已经好了 关火
The dumplings are cooked. Turn off the heat
# 这饺子必须汤是热的
The dumplings must be hot (when serving)
# 不然的话这饺子放到里边它就沉底了
Otherwise it will sink to the bottom of the soup
# 如果凉了以后不行
It will not work if it is cold
# 太漂亮了太有食欲了
So beautiful! So tempting!
# 还一小花饺子
Look, there is a dumplings with patterned wrapper
# 菠饺啤酒清炖鸭
Spinach dumplings with beer braised duck
# 跟我们网友说一下
Dear friends,
# 这个锅实在是不好起 烫
It is too difficult to take the plate out of the pot, too hot.
# 我们就放在蒸屉上了
So we leave it in the steamer
# 家里边条件有限
Devices are limited at home.
# 二伯 谢谢大爷 这给我
Er Bai. -Thank you Da Ye. -Give it to me
# 今儿待遇不低
I am treated well today
# 先尝汤 后吃肉
Taste the soup first, then eat the meat
# 还这味儿真好
This is delicious!
# 这葱姜使得恰当 真合适
The spring onions and ginger are used properly
# 多了也不行少了也不行
Neither too much nor too few
# 它有淡淡的那种味道 配鸭子
It contains light flavor (of the spring onions and ginger), pairing well with the duck
# 四儿你拍着 我给你盛一碗
Si er, you keep filming and I will get you a bowl of the dish
# 这在家里边来一碗
Have a bowl of this at home
# 小四你待会吃就知道了
Xiao Si, you will understand when you eat it
# 一会儿这一大锅我都给他吃了 真好
I will have the whole pot later, so delicious
# 大爷先来 必须你先来
Da Ye, you eat first. -Please, you must have it first
# 其实我早就馋了
I have been craving for it for very long.
# 先喝汤 尝尝热啤酒的味道是什么味道
Drink the soup first, try and see what the heated beer tastes like
# 这汤喝出滋补的味道来了
The soup tastes nourishing
# 其实没下过多的（料）
In fact, there is not too much (ingredients)
# 味精鸡精咱都不放
No MSG or chicken bouillon powder
# 就搁点盐 搁点胡椒
Just some salt, pepper,
# 搁点黄酒 搁上啤酒
Huangjiu rice wine and beer
# 来块鸭肉 鸭肉的软烂
Have a piece of duck. The duck meat is tender and soft
# 是根据自己的口味 可以更烂一点
To fit your own taste, it can be further tenderized.
# 因为咱们现场的条件还是有点约束
Our conditions here are still a bit limiting.
# 特别合适您看 它一咬
It fits you very well, take a bite
# 那时候就这道菜征服了无数人
This dish has won many people’s heart back then
# 也接待过无数外宾
And served numerous foreign guests
# 应该说受到了宾客的喜欢
It is very popular among gourmands
# 今天大爷重新再现这道菜
Today, Da Ye reproduce the cuisine
# 心里边暖乎乎的
It is heart-warming
# 你看汤清味美
See, the soup is clear and the taste is delicious
# 饺子的味道非常浓 肉香味非常浓
The taste of the dumplings is rich with mellow meat flavor
# 一咬汁出来了
Take a bite and the soup spread out
# 鸭子那种清香 投料这种巧妙
The light aroma of the duck and the skills of adding ingredients properly
# 使这个鸭子吃不出啤酒味来
Avoid the duck being taste like beer
# 一点鸭腥的味没有
No gamey taste of the duck
# 好吃的味道 年代的记忆
Delicious taste and old memories.
# 大爷的情怀 技艺的传承
The passion of Da Ye, to inherit the legacy
# 谢谢二伯 谢谢四民
Thank you Er Bai! Thank you Si Min!
# 把这汤都喝了 必须喝
Drink all the soup, must drink it
# 大爷你看我会表扬人吧
Da Ye, I am good at complimenting people, am I not?
# 你太会表扬人了
You are so good at complimenting people!
# 你表扬的我很激动
Your compliment makes me very excited!